CINDY WONG

Software Engineer

(347) 591 9013 · cindywongdev@gmail.com · Brooklyn, NY · in/cindywongdev · github.com/cindywongdev

Brooklyn-born and raised software engineer with a passion for making a positive impact on the people and world around me. With a bachelor's degree in psychology and experience in customer service, I aim to tackle problems with a user-centered approach, understanding the human behind the screen. I am a quick learner who is able to fuse my proficiency in graphic design software with newly learned technologies such as React and CSS, allowing me to develop effective and elegant technical solutions.

SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Python | Libraries and Frameworks - Express.js, React.js, Node.js, jQuery, SASS, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, Flask | Databases - MongoDB, PostgreSQL | Other - Agile, Scrum, RESTful Routing, JSON, MVC frameworks, Postman, Github, VSCode, Trello, Figma, Adobe Suite (Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, XD), Microsoft Office, Canva

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Quotidian: responsive fullstack to-do list

- Developed a responsive to-do list for users to track, categorize, and check off to-dos.
- Built a full stack application in 1 week with full **CRUD** operations hitting all RESTful API calls. <u>Live Demo. Frontend repo here.</u>
- Created an API using Django to enable reliable access, storage, and manipulation of user data. Backend repo here.
- Technologies used: React, Javascript, Bootstrap, Python, Django, PostgreSQL

theraNotes: responsive fullstack note tracking app

- Created a notetracker application for those in therapy to keep track of notes for each session and view their progress over time.
- Implemented session-based user authentication for security and data management.
- Utilized a MEN stack (MongoDB, Express, Node) to build a full stack application in 1 week with full create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations hitting all RESTful API calls. Deployed on Render. Repo here.
- Styled the application to be both web and mobile-responsive using CSS3 with flexbox and grid layouts.

MyEvents: responsive fullstack event tracking app

- Collaborated with a team of 4 developers to create an event tracker application for users to track events.
- Utilized a MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) to build a full stack application in 1 week with full CRUD operations hitting all RESTful API calls. <u>Deployed on Netlify</u>. <u>Frontend repo here</u>.
- Created an API using Express to enable reliable access, storage, and manipulation of user data. Backend repo here.
- Technologies used: React, Javascript, Bootstrap

Excuse Generator: random generator application

- Created an excuse generator application making fetch calls to the Excuser API. Deployed on Vercel. Repo here.
- Technologies used: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Mural (wireframing tool), VSCode, Vercel

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TESO LIFE, Store Associate | Brooklyn, New York

July 2022 - Present

- Demonstrated ability to provide exceptional customer service by offering in-store assistance to customers.
- Strong mathematical skills and attention to detail, efficiently processing cash, credit, debit, and voucher program payments.
- Interacted with customers in a warm and friendly manner to enhance the overall shopping experience.

Binghamton University, Graphic Designer and Student Office Assistant | Binghamton, New York

Sept 2019 - May 2022

- Developed effective promotional posters for department events and classes, resulting in increased attendance and engagement.
- Utilized technical skills to digitize documents, increasing workflow efficiency and ensuring timely delivery to faculty members.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY | REMOTE

Software Engineering Flex Immersive

Sept 2022 - Present

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twenty-four-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

BINGHAMTON UNIVERSITY | BINGHAMTON, NY

Bachelor of Arts in Psychology | Minor in Graphic Design

GPA: 3.91 | Honors: Phi Beta Kappa, Summa Cum Laude, Dean's List

Aug 2018 - May 2022